Greg Sandell

Los Angeles, CA

(213) 479-0790 • GREG.SANDELL@GMAIL.COM • Portfolio/code: gregsandell.com

Skills

I have over ten years experience in Front End Development of web-based applications, playing a delivery role in medium to large enterprise projects in Java/Linux/Open Source environments. I focus on the Front End programming logic for transactional web pages, and can deploy designs in HTML5 and CSS3 as well. I have 13 years experience with Agile methodology, tooling, TDD and automated test coverage.

Technology stack (ordered roughly by recency and strength): React 15, Redux, AngularJS 1.4S, Node.js, Javascript, Git, Jasmine/Mocha/Sinon/Chai, Selenium/Nightwatch, LaunchDarkly, Advanced Rest Client, WebStorm, Rally, Jenkins, LES, API Blueprint, Nexus, Bootstrap, ExtJS 4.0.7, Jasmine 2.3, Fisheye/Crucible, Eclipse 4.4/Luna, jMeter 2.13, Oracle, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, Maven 4, HTML5, CSS3, Tomcat 6, GlassFish 3.1.2, JEE 6, JSP, Artifactory, mysql, SQL Server.

Experience

APR 2016 - PRESENT

Ten-X, Irvine, CA - Sr. Software Engineer

- Developer for hosted web application auction.com, Real Estate auction transaction platform
- Wrote presentation layer and application logic in AngularJS, React, ES6, Javascript & Python
- · Built apps in using tools: nodeJS, Webpack, npm, nvm
- Wrote demo with demographic maps for commercial Real Estate using Esri's ArcGIS javascript API
- Virtualization of Windows & Linux on OSX with Vagrant, VirtualBox, and Docker
- Wrote QA Automation tests for AngularJS and React components using Selenium and Nightwatch
- · Added Omniture tracking to and LaunchDarkly feature flags to applications
- · Collaborated with Back End team on design and troubleshooting of REST and JSON-based services
- Tooling & Collaboration: eslint, Git, SourceTree, Jenkins, WebStorm, Slack, Jira, Confluence
- · Frequent travel to San Mateo, CA office

OCT 2015 - MAR 2016

John Deere, Los Angeles, CA - Front End Developer Consultant

- Developer for hosted web application 'Sales Center', a 'build-a-Deere' tool for sales reps.
- Wrote presentation layer and application logic in AngularJS/Javascript
- · Wrote tests for AngularJS controllers, views, directives and services in Mocha, Sinon and Chai
- · Collaborated with Back End team on design and troubleshooting of REST/JSON-based services
- API Blueprint to mock REST services for local development
- AngularJS libs: angular-ui-router, angular-translate, angular-bootstrap, ng-infinite-scroll
- Tooling & Collaboration: eslint, Git, SourceTree, Jenkins, WebStorm, Hangouts, Lync, Flowdock
- 100% remote work (HQ in Moline, IL), some travel

NOV 2014 - AUG 2015

CyberCoders, Irvine, CA - Front End Java Developer

- Developer for hosted web application 'Compass', a CRM platform for Recruiters.
- Wrote application logic in Javascript, ExtJS, Ajax/JSON programming.
- · Created forms, panels, grids and other UI widgets from ExtJS components

- Stress-tested app with jMeter, 5-250 concurrent users.
- · Wrote Jasmine unit tests for project's custom ExtJS components

NOV 2013 - JUNE 2014

Sears Holding Corporation, Chicago, IL - Developer

- · Member of Core Mobile team supporting mobile version of sears.com E-Commerce site
- Wrote AngularJS controllers, views, and services for new website features.
- Deployed UIs in HTML5/CSS3 from Photoshop PSDs
- Designed REST web services in coordination with backend team and DBAs.
- Integrated features of the *Shop Your Way* loyalty card into the mobile experience.
- Implemented Shop Your Way Max (Sears version of Amazon Prime).

AUG 2012 - AUG 2013

Pathfinder Software, Chicago, IL - Senior Software Engineer

- Wrote mobile apps (iPhone, iPad) for medical clients, using hybrid web/iOS, jQuery Mobile, JSON, AngularJS, Trigger.io, TestFlight, and Rails/Heroku
- Deployed UIs in HTML5/CSS3 from Photoshop PSDs
- · Clients included Kimberly-Clark, Haemonetics, Amer. Assn. of Critical Care Nurses
- Lead developer on AACN Bedside which converted legacy laminated-card media into iPhone app, including in-app purchasing through Apple AppStore
- Delivered MetroPulse Chicago, a Rich Media website frontend for census and demographic data (demo: http://bit.ly/1EGoNB2)
- Delivered *ContinuCare*, an iPad 'concierge' app to connect heart patients, their nurses and caregivers, written in AngularJS with backend in Rails/Heroku
- Delivered Automated Whole Blood Collector, a blood drive simulation sales tool for the iPad, in AngularJS

APR 2010 - AUG 2012

Truven Health Analytics, Chicago, IL - Senior Software Engineer

- Developed hosted web applications *CareDiscovery* and *IntegrationDiscovery*, Business Intelligence and data mining tools for the Healthcare Industry.
- Created servlet- and portal-based enterprise web applications for IBM Websphere Portal 5, Tomcat 6 & Glassfish in mixed JEE 6 and J2EE 1.4 environment.
- Implemented screens in HTML/CSS from designer specs
- Wrote User Interfaces and Ajax in Javascript & jQuery, promoting reusable patterns, functional programming, and closures.
- Authored PL/SQL queries in Toad to work against a 4 TB Oracle OLAP (Data Warehouse) database, for deployment in Web Services.
- Helped transition team from waterfall to agile approach by introducing Maven2, Artifactory Repository Server, Jenkins/Continuous Integration, Mercurial source control and TDD practices.

OCT 2008 - MAR 2010

iCrossing, Chicago, IL - Senior Software Engineer

- Developed hosted web application *Merchantize*, a workflow tool for managing clients' Paid Search campaigns with major search and shopping engines (Google, Yahoo, MSN, NexTag, PriceGrabber).
- Developed a 3-tier daily product feed lifecycle with Perl, Bash, Java, XML and Unix cron.
- Developed custom reports in Apache POI for clients for clients Sears, The Gap, Hilton, Lands End, LEGO, and Williams Sonoma.
- Performed regular support of application database including resolving data integrity issues, synchronizing with remote search engine data, bulk keyword deletes and cost-per-click changes.

Chicago Tribune, Chicago, IL - Senior Internet Applications Developer

- Developed web software and content management behind all of Tribune Corp's newspaper, radio and television websites, including Chicago Tribune, LA Times, Red Eye.
- Developed code in Java 1.5 on J2EE platform including Oracle Application Server 10g, Oracle DB 10g, FAST search server, Sun Webserver (iPlanet) and TopLink 9.0 for web services.
- · Created scheduled jobs for sweeping expired database content.
- Created JMeter test plans and reporting tools to simulate heavy load on high-profile chicagotribune.com website.

Education

Northwestern University, Evanston, IL - PhD Music Theory

Cross-disciplinary curriculum including music theory, auditory perception, computer science and music synthesizer research. Dissertation: http://bit.ly/10A4q8t

Eastman School of Music, Rochester, NY - MA Music Theory

Analysis techniques on classical and 20th Century music. Formal computer programming studies. Thesis on Edgard Varèse.

California State University, Los Angeles, CA - BM Piano Performance

Performed Junior and Senior recitals, placed in competitions, and performed Beethoven concerto with orchestra.

Certifications

March 2005: Sun Certified Web Component Developer for J2EE 1.4 (SCWCD)

Apr 2004: Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform 1.4 (SCJP)

References

Available on request.